

CONTACT



omarsaifabir@gmail.com



+8801521439053



Kallyanpur, Dhaka, Bangladesh

TECHNICAL SKILS

SolidWorks, Keyshot, Autodesk Inventor, Fusion 360, Python, Matlab, FARO, Autodesk Recap, 3DS Maya, Filmora, MS Excel, Microsoft Office Suit, Google Office Suit, Adobe PhotoShop

SOFT SKILS

Leadership, Design Thinking, Collaboration, Adaptability, Diversity, Management, Analytical Thinking, Disciplined, Rationality

LANGUAGE

English **Fluent**

Bengali **Native**

OMAR SAIF

MECHANICAL ENGINEER | CSWA



ABOUT

SolidWorks certified design engineer with three years of experience in 3D consumer products, industrial machines and innovative solutions. Currently based in Bangladesh, I am a self-driven adaptive learner who is always keen on efficient skillsets for sustainable growth, both for myself and, as a team player; my team/organization.



JOB EXPERIENCE

| October, 2021 – April, 2022 | Walton Hi-Tech Industries PLC |
|-----------------------------|--------------------------------------|
| | Sr. Deputy Assistant Director |
| | Research and Innovation Department |
| | VRF Model Manager |
| | Quality of life Improvement for VRF, |
| | Chiller and HVAC systems for |
| | Customers and End-Users |

| May, 2019 – September, 2021 | Brightbirds Intelligence Junior Mechanical Engineer |
|-----------------------------|---|
| | Sheet Metal Specialist |
| | Product Render Specialist |
| | Responsible for bringing new technologies |
| | Meeting Clients and Dutch Colleagues |



EDUCATION

| 2013 – 2018 | Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology BSc. In Mechanical Engineering |
|-------------|---|
| 2010 – 2012 | Notre Dame College Higher Secondary School Certificate, Science |
| 2008 – 2010 | Dhaka Residential Model College Secondary School Certificate, Science |



NOTABLE CAREER/PROJECT ACHIEVEMENTS

- Owner of 130+ Industrial Design Solutions
- Co-Designer, Student Project, James Webb Space Telescope (NASA)
- Design & Fabrication Head, Undergraduate Thesis (bionic engineering)
- Designer, Monowheel (Undergraduate Project)

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified SolidWorks Associate, CSWA Dassault Systems **Innovation Through Design** University of Sydney **Supply Chain Logistics Rutgers University Python for Beginners** Udemy (Yasin Marco) **Introduction to Business Management** Kings College London

HOBBIES











Music

Writing

REFERENCES



Al Mamun Rabbe

Sr. Motion Designer Mail: al.mamun.rabbe@gmail.com



Martin Tomitsch

Professor of Interaction Design Director of Innovation University of Sydney Mail: martin.tomitsch@sydney.edu.au



- Squad Leader, Sabre Squad
- Captain, Intra-Department Cricket Team
- Founding CEO
- In Game Leader
- Alumni Member
- Group Captain, Group 7
- **Founding CEO**

Tactical Gaming AUST (University) Project 317 (e-Sports) Project 317 Valorant Roster NDC Nature Study Club Notre Dame College Hungry Fools (book club)

I, hereby, declare every information included in this resume is accurate and true to my knowledge.

> **Signature** August 30, 2022